{
    "exam_name": "C Programming Set 1",
    "total_marks": 20,
    "time_limit": 20,
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br>int x = 5;<br>x = x++ + ++x;<br>printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "5",
                "B": "10",
                "C": "11",
                "D": "12"
            },
            "correct_answer": "D"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int main()<br>{<br>printf(\"Hello World! %d \\n\", x);<br>return 0;<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "Hello World! x;",
                "b": "Hello World! followed by a junk value",
                "c": "Compile time error",
                "d": "Hello World!"
            },
            "correct_answer": "c"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int main()<br>{<br>int y = 10000;<br>int y = 34;<br>printf(\"Hello World! %d\\n\", y);<br>return 0;<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "Compile time error",
                "b": "Hello World! 34",
                "c": "Hello World! 10000",
                "d": "Hello World! followed by a junk value"
            },
            "correct_answer": "a"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will happen if the following C code is executed?<br><br><pre>int main()<br>{<br>int main = 3;<br>printf(\"%d\", main);<br>return 0;<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "It will cause a compile-time error",
                "b": "It will cause a run-time error",
                "c": "It will run without any error and prints 3",
                "d": "It will experience infinite looping"
            },
            "correct_answer": "c"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int i = 5;<br>printf(\"%d\", i++ + i-- - ++i);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "5",
                "B": "6",
                "C": "7",
                "D": "8"
            },
            "correct_answer": "C"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 4, y = 2;<br>x <<= y;<br>printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "2",
                "B": "4",
                "C": "8",
                "D": "16"
            },
            "correct_answer": "D"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5, y = 3;<br>printf(\"%d\", x & y);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "0",
                "B": "1",
                "C": "3",
                "D": "5"
            },
            "correct_answer": "B"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5, y = 3;<br>printf(\"%d\", x | y);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "0",
                "B": "1",
                "C": "3",
                "D": "7"
            },
            "correct_answer": "D"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5, y = 3;<br>printf(\"%d\", x ^ y);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "0",
                "B": "1",
                "C": "3",
                "D": "7"
            },
            "correct_answer": "D"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5;<br>printf(\"%d\", ~x);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "-5",
                "B": "-6",
                "C": "-4",
                "D": "4"
            },
            "correct_answer": "B"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int arr[] = {1, 2, 3};<br>printf(\"%d\", arr[5]);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "1",
                "B": "2",
                "C": "3",
                "D": "Garbage value"
            },
            "correct_answer": "D"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int main()<br>{<br>int a[5] = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5};<br>int i;<br>for (i = 0; i < 5; i++)<br>  if ((char)a[i] == '5')<br>    printf(\"%d\\n\", a[i]);<br>  else<br>    printf(\"FAIL\\n\");<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "The compiler will flag an error",
                "b": "The program will compile and print the output 5",
                "c": "The program will compile and print the ASCII value of 5",
                "d": "The program will compile and print FAIL for 5 times"
            },
            "correct_answer": "d"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int main()<br>{<br>signed char chr;<br>chr = 128;<br>printf(\"%d\\n\", chr);<br>return 0;<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "128",
                "b": "-128",
                "c": "Depends on the compiler",
                "d": "None of the mentioned"
            },
            "correct_answer": "b"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> char str[] = \"Hello\";<br>printf(\"%c\", str[5]);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "H",
                "B": "e",
                "C": "l",
                "D": "Garbage value"
            },
            "correct_answer": "D"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int main()<br>{<br>char c;<br>int i = 0;<br>FILE *file;<br>file = fopen(\"test.txt\", \"w+\");<br>fprintf(file, \"%c\", 'a');<br>fprintf(file, \"%c\", -1);<br>fprintf(file, \"%c\", 'b');<br>fclose(file);<br>file = fopen(\"test.txt\", \"r\");<br>while ((c = fgetc(file)) != -1)<br>\tprintf(\"%c\", c);<br>return 0;<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "a",
                "b": "Infinite loop",
                "c": "Depends on what fgetc returns",
                "d": "Depends on the compiler"
            },
            "correct_answer": "b"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int main()<br>{<br>float f1 = 0.1;<br>if (f1 == 0.1)<br>\tprintf(\"equal\\n\");<br>else<br>\tprintf(\"not equal\\n\");<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "equal",
                "b": "not equal",
                "c": "output depends on the compiler",
                "d": "error"
            },
            "correct_answer": "b"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> char str[] = \"Hello\";<br>printf(\"%s\", str + 2);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "Hello",
                "B": "llo",
                "C": "lo",
                "D": "Error"
            },
            "correct_answer": "C"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code on a 32-bit machine?<br><br><pre>int main()<br>{<br>int x = 10000;<br>double y = 56;<br>int *p = &x;<br>double *q = &y;<br>printf(\"p and q are %d and %d\", sizeof(p), sizeof(q));<br>return 0;<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "p and q are 4 and 4",
                "b": "p and q are 4 and 8",
                "c": "compiler error",
                "d": "p and q are 2 and 8"
            },
            "correct_answer": "b"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> char *ptr = \"Hello\";<br>printf(\"%s\", ptr++);<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "A": "Hello",
                "B": "ello",
                "C": "llo",
                "D": "Compiler error"
            },
            "correct_answer": "B"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following C code on a 64-bit machine?<br><br><pre>union Sti<br>{<br>int nu;<br>char m;<br>};<br>int main()<br>{<br>union Sti s;<br>printf(\"%d\", sizeof(s));<br>return 0;<br>}</pre>",
            "options": {
                "a": "8",
                "b": "5",
                "c": "9",
                "d": "4"
            },
            "correct_answer": "a"
        }
    ]
}
